Ralph T. Walker Papers
Ralph T. Walker Papers
1916-1970
Walker, Ralph, 1889-1973.
50.5 linear ft.
Papers of the American architect. Correspondence, articles, manuscript essays, speeches, notes and notebooks, photographs, project files, sketches, clippings, and scrapbooks.
148730
Biographical History
Ralph Thomas Walker (1889-1973) was an American architect. He attended Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) and studied with Rhode Island architect Howard K. Hilton. In 1916 he went to work for the New York firm of McKenzie, Voorhees and Gmelin, where he remained for the rest of his career. In 1955 he led a group of architects sent to Berlin to participate in planning for the International Building Exhibition (IBA) to be held in 1957; as part of this effort, he and his team proposed building a Congress Hall, to "promote international understanding through the advancement of culture, education and science." The Benjamin Franklin Foundation, a joint German-American organization with Walker as its chairman, was created to oversee the planning and construction of the Berlin Congress Hall, completed in 1957. The Foundation went on to spend another 13 years in reconstruction projects in and around Berlin.
Most of Walker's buildings are in New York City, including the AT&T building on Broadway, the iconic One Wall Street (originally the Irving Trust Building), and the Barclay-Vesey Building (later known as the Verizon Building, severely damaged during the September 11, 2001 World Trade Center attacks).
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Ralph T. Walker Papers spans nearly sixty years, almost the entire career of the American architect. The collection is divided into 16 series.
Notes contains Walker's notes on a variety of topics. Writings contains rough drafts, speeches, articles, essays, poetry, and pamphlets. Published material relates to Walker and/or his work and includes clippings, pamphlets, and miscellaneous unrelated published material.
Five Scrapbooks contain material relating to the American Institute of Architects, the Berlin Congress Hall, and other jobs. Sketches, some of which are oversize, includes pieces relating to specific jobs (MIT Library, Barclay-Vesey Building, Petroleum Building, Philadelphia Opera House) and to various topics (imaginary buildings, Rotch Scholarship, West Indies, World's Fairs). Photographs are of various subjects, both personal and professional, and include numerous glass slides used for teaching. News clippings also cover a range of subjects such as Robert Moses, city planning, and food. Alphabetical and Chronological files are simply that -- files on various subjects arranged alphabetically or chronologically, respectively.
Berlin files and Trinidad files relate to Walker's work in those two locations; the former concerns the Berlin Congress Hall, part of the International Building Exhibition in 1957, with which Walker was involved both as architect and as chairman of the Benjamin Franklin Foundation. Massachusetts Institute of Technology Library files and International Union of Architects files contain assorted material relating to Walker's ongoing relationship with those two organizations.
Literature and T.S. Eliot contain an assortment of non-architecture-related items, including French literature and poetry, literary criticism, articles, and other miscellanea. A small amount of Miscellaneous material completes the collection.
Arrangement of the Collection
Writings and Published material are subdivided alphabetically by type, then arranged alphabetically by title. Except for the Chronological files, all other material is arranged alphabetically within its series.
Subject and Genre Headings
Architects; Walker, Ralph, 1889-1973 -- Archives.; Architects -- United States.; Architectural design.; Architectural drawing -- United States -- 20th century.; Architecture -- United States.; Architecture -- American.; Architecture -- United States -- 20th century.; Articles.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Essays.; Manuscripts for publication.; Notebooks.; Notes (documents); Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Sketches.; Speeches (documents); Architects.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Ralph Walker, Mrs. Ralph Walker.
Inventory
- Notes
  - Aesthetics (Box 1)
  - Architects' Fees (Box 1)
  - Far East, October-November, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Housing (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Notebooks, 2 folders (Box 1)
- Writings
  - Rough Drafts
    - 1929-1939, 3 folders (Box 1)
    - 1941-1943, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - 1946-1961, 5 folders (Box 1)
    - Architecture and Machines, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Architecture in Nature (Box 1)
    - Camouflage (Box 2)
    - Caribbean (Box 2)
    - City, 4 folders (Box 2)
    - Each Day Anew (Box 2)
    - Fragments (Box 2)
    - Frank Lloyd Wright (Box 2)
    - Le Corbusier (Box 2)
    - Luxembourg (Box 2)
    - Machine, Aesthetics, and Architecture (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous, 4 folders (Box 2)
    - Nixon (Box 2)
    - Notes on the Theatre, 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Rise of the Factory Style (Box 2)
    - Teaching Architecture (Box 2)
    - Telephone Building (Box 2)
    - Theatre (Box 2)
    - Venice (Box 2)
    - West Indies (Box 2)
    - World's Fairs - Chicago and New York (Box 2)
  - Speeches
    - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Finished Articles (spiral bound typescripts)
    - The Aesthetic Slum at "The President's Meadow" (Box 2)
    - Architectural Engineering (Box 2)
    - Architecture and Today's Living (Box 2)
    - Arts Forum - Columbia University (Box 2)
    - Bauhaus (Box 2)
    - The Birth of an Idea (Box 2)
    - Centennial Medal of Honor (Box 2)
    - The City (Box 2)
    - The City (Box 3)
    - City Planning (Box 3)
    - Classics vs. Poppycocks and "Hit Parade" (Box 3)
    - Congress Hall - Berlin (Box 3)
    - Congress Hall - Dedication, September, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence with Douglas Hakell, 1967 (Box 3)
    - Designing Buildings for Research (Box 3)
    - Diregarding Media (Box 3)
    - Diversions (Box 3)
    - Each Day Anew (several chapters) (Box 3)
    - The Education of an Architect (Box 3)
    - The Essence of Tradition (Box 3)
    - Fragmentary Culture (Box 3)
    - Guggenheim - Lincoln Center (Box 3)
    - Impact of Automobile (Box 3)
    - In Search of a Culture - The Exacting Word (Box 3)
    - In Search of a Culture - The Exacting Word (Box 4)
    - The Machine, Aesthetics, and Architecture (Box 4)
    - Masonry Walls in Modular Construction (Box 4)
    - Mr. Nixon (Box 4)
    - Montclair Library (Box 4)
    - Notes on the Theatre (Box 4)
    - The Overwhelming Sense of Bigness (Box 4)
    - Paradise Here and Now (Box 4)
    - A Program for Urban Research (Box 4)
    - Report of the Committee on Architects (Box 4)
    - Richfest, Congress Hall - Berlin (Box 4)
    - Rise of the Factory Style (Box 4)
    - The Sayings of Louise (Box 4)
    - Seventy-six Going on Seventy-seven (Box 5)
    - A Straw Man or Two (Box 5)
    - Tax Reform and Government of Cities (Box 5)
    - The Urbanity of Form (Box 5)
    - Why Ornament? (Box 5)
    - Your Profession and Mine (Box 5)
  - Essays, in bindings
    - 1941, 1 volume (Box 5)
    - 1949, 14 volumes (Box 5)
    - 1950, 10 volumes (Box 5)
    - 1951, 6 volumes (Box 5)
    - 1951, 4 volumes (Box 6)
    - 1952, 10 volumes (Box 6)
    - 1953, 3 volumes (Box 6)
    - 1954, 6 volumes (Box 6)
    - 1955, 2 volumes (Box 6)
    - 1956, 6 volumes (Box 6)
    - 1957, 7 volumes (Box 6)
    - 1958, 2 volumes (Box 6)
    - 1959, 3 volumes (Box 6)
    - 1960, 1 volume (Box 6)
  - Journal Articles
    - "The American Institute of Architects, 1944-1957", 48 issues (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous, 20 issues (Box 7)
  - Anthology Article
    - "New Screen Techniques" (Box 7)
  - Books
    - The Fly in the Amber, 5 volumes (Box 7)
  - Booklets and Pamphlets
    - Ralph Walker: The American Institute of Architects, 1921-1961, 11 copies (Box 7)
    - London Winter, 1943; 2 copies (Box 8)
    - Humans + Materials=Architecture
      - Series I, 1939-1945; 15 copies (Box 8)
      - Series II, 1946-1947; 4 copies (Box 8)
    - Frank Lloyd Wright, 1955 (Box 8)
    - Diversions, 1965 (Box 8)
    - What is Beautiful; What is Good, 1965; 2 copies (Box 8)
  - Poetry Pamphlets
    - The Branch, 1949-1950; 1 copy (Box 8)
    - Vidi, 1951; 4 copies (Box 8)
    - Screaming Egos, Fragile Ids, 1966; 29 copies (Box 8)
    - Vagrants, 1966; 25 copies (Box 8)
    - Cyma Recta, 1968-1969; 11 copies (Box 8)
    - Ode to Peace, 1971; 2 copies (Box 8)
    - Collected Poems (Box 8)
- Published material
  - Voorhees, Walker, Smith and Smith, miscellaneous pamphlets (Box 9)
  - News Clippings
    - The New York Times Magazine, 3 issues (Oversize 3)
  - Pamplets that mention Ralph Walker, 15 pamphlets (Box 10)
  - Unrelated Published Material
    - Books, 5 volumes, 1 folder (Box 10)
    - Journals, 15 issues (Box 10)
    - Pamphlets
      - General, 14 pamphlets (Box 11)
      - "Blueprint #1" (Oversize 3)
      - Columbia University, 3 folders (Box 11)
      - Dartmouth Eye Institute (Box 11)
      - Graduate Programs (Box 11)
      - Lavenburg Foundation - The Village in the City (Oversize 3)
      - Massachusetts Institute of Technology Library, 3 copies (Oversize 3)
      - Miscellaneous, 4 folders (Box 11)
      - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 12)
      - Urban Research Bureau - Princeton, 4 folders (Box 12)
      - Washington, D.C. - Downtown (3 pamphlets) (Oversize 3)
      - World's Fair, 4 folders (Box 12)
    - Pamphlets bound in folders, 7 pamphlets (Box 12)
- Scrapbooks
  - The American Institute of Architects, Centennial Medal of Honor - Letterbook, 1957 (Oversize 3)
  - Berlin Congress Hall, 1957 (Oversize 4)
  - Coty Plant Plans (Oversize 4)
  - Trinidad Drawings (Oversize 4)
  - Permanent World Capitol - Flushing (Oversize 4)
  - Venice Sketches - F. Hopkinson Smith (Oversize 4)
- Sketches
  - Across a Crowded Room, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - All Fellow Travelers (Box 12)
  - Art Commission (Box 13)
  - Buildings and Gardens (Box 13)
  - Buildings (Imaginary) (Box 13)
  - Cartoons (Box 13)
  - Christmas Cards (Box 13)
  - Christmas Cards - Finished, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Figure Studies (Box 13)
  - Franklin Delano Roosevelt Memorial Competition (Box 13)
  - Interior (Box 14)
  - Library - Massachusetts Institute of Technology (Box 14)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology (Box 14)
  - Men, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Mounted Sketches
    - Barclay-Vesey Building, 2 folders (Oversize 6)
    - Bedroom Display - Metropolitan Museum of Art (Oversize 6)
    - Belgian Embassy (Oversize 6)
    - Brooklyn Edison Substation (Oversize 6)
    - Child's History of Architecture (Oversize 6)
    - City Hall (Oversize 7)
    - Domestic Scale (Oversize 7)
    - Drawings - Odds and Ends, 2 folders (Oversize 7)
    - Enduring Memory (Oversize 7)
    - Houses (Oversize 7)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology Library (Oversize 8)
    - Miscellaneous Photographs – Architecture (Oversize 8)
    - Nicaro (Oversize 8)
    - Perspective Studies (Oversize 8)
    - Petroleum Building (Oversize 8)
    - Philadelphia Opera House - Tapestries (Oversize 8)
    - Photographs (Oversize 9)
    - Planning - Large Scale, Chicago and New York (Oversize 9)
    - Rotch Scholarship, 2 folders (Oversize 9)
    - Sketches (Oversize 9)
    - San Clemente, Rome (Oversize 9)
    - Woodrow Wilson Memorial – Princeton (Oversize 10)
    - World's Fairs, 5 folders (Oversize 10)
    - Rotch Traveling Scholarship, 1916; 3 large sketches (Oversize 11)
    - Sketches for printed matter (covers, cards, etc.) mostly relating to Christmas, 23 sketches mounted to 15x20 inches (Oversize 12)
  - New York World's Fair: General Electric and AT&T, 1939 (Box 14)
  - Printing Suggestions (Box 14)
  - "Seeking a Job" - Bertram Goodhue (Box 14)
  - Travel (Box 14)
  - Watercolors (Box 14)
  - West Indies (Box 14)
  - World War I (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous Sketches (Oversize 5)
- Photographs
  - Applied Photography Magazine, 1934; 1 issue (Oversize 3)
  - Architectural Design, 3 folders (Box 14)
  - Architectural projects (Oversize 3)
  - Composition Studies (Box 14)
  - Each Day Anew (Box 14)
  - Glass lantern slides
    - Japan (Box 35)
    - Art/architecture teaching/lecture slides (4 boxes) (Box 36-39)
    - Art/architecture teaching/lecture slides, series on the triangle (shape) (Box 40)
    - Art/architecture teaching/lecture slides, also film negatives (Box 41)
    - Art/architecture teaching/lecture slides (Box 42)
  - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Modern Architecture, 5 folders (Box 15)
  - Mounted photographs (Oversize 1)
  - Mounted photographs (Oversize 2)
  - Negatives (Box 43)
  - Notes on the Theatre - Photostats (Box 15)
  - Oriental and Indian Design (Box 15)
  - Photostats (Box 15)
  - Sky Scrapers, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Walker, Ralph - Portraits and Candids (Box 15)
  - Walker Birthday Party (Box 15)
  - World's Fair - Chicago, 1930; 3 folders (Box 15)
  - Photo Album - Tribune Tower Competition, 1 volume (Box 15)
  - Photo Albums - United Nations, Hunter College, 1946; 3 volumes (Box 16)
  - Postcard photographs (Box 43)
  - Postcard photographs (Box 44)
  - Ralph Walker Portraits (Oversize 3)
  - Miscellaneous (Oversize 3)
- News clippings
  - Art (Box 16)
  - The City (Box 16)
  - City Planning (Box 16)
  - Education (Box 16)
  - Finance (Box 16)
  - Food (Box 16)
  - Foreign Policy (Box 16)
  - Magazine Clippings, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Magazine Clippings - Form and Color (Box 16)
  - Miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 16)
  - Miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 17)
  - Moses, Robert (Box 17)
  - Poetry Reviews (Box 17)
  - Theatre, 2 folders (Box 17)
- Alphabetical files
  - Cartoons (Box 17)
  - Galleys (Box 17)
  - Housing (Box 17)
  - Illustrations - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Le Corbusier (Box 17)
  - Syllabus - History of Architecture Course (Box 17)
  - Tax Payers' Committee - New Castle (Box 17)
  - Theatre, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Trinidad, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Washington, D.C. (Box 18)
  - World's Fair (Box 18)
  - Wright, Frank Lloyd, 3 folders (Box 18)
  - Zoning - New Castle, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - The Aesthetic Slum at the President's Meadow (Box 18)
  - Addresses, Articles, and Correspondence, 1927-1949; 3 folders (Box 18)
  - Addresses, Articles, and Correspondence, 1950 (Box 19)
  - Articles (Box 19)
  - Advantgarde (Box 19)
  - Bauhaus, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Bibliography (Box 19)
  - Biography (Box 19)
  - Brewer (Box 19)
  - Chappaqua Library Speech (Box 19)
  - City Planning (Box 19)
  - City Planning - Mayors' Committee (Box 19)
  - Contemporary Design (Box 19)
  - Correspondence - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Each Day Anew (Box 19)
  - Early Architectural Training (Box 19)
  - The End of an Era (moved to Box 3[?]) (Box 19)
  - Feinstein, Sol (Box 19)
  - Geometry (Box 19)
  - Gropins (Box 19)
  - Invitations, Programs and Awards, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Japan Trip, 4 folders (Box 19)
  - Kallen, Horace (Box 19)
  - Kamin, Alfred (Box 19)
  - Land Use Density (Box 20)
  - Lavanburg Foundation, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Literature of Fun City (Box 20)
  - MacMillan - The Education of an Architect (Box 20)
  - Maps (Box 20)
  - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - New Yorker (Box 20)
  - Paranoia, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Saarinen, Eero (Box 20)
  - Sitte Book (Box 20)
  - Slum Clearance (Box 20)
  - Syracuse University Library, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Taxes, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Tennyson Society (Box 20)
  - Theatre (Box 20)
  - They Were Giants - General (Box 20)
  - They Were Giants - Frank Lloyd Wright (Box 20)
  - They Were Giants - LeCorbusier (Box 20)
  - Unesco Building – Paris (Box 20)
  - Westchester County, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Work Orders (Box 20)
- Chronological files
  - 1926
    - "The Nation's Roll of Honor (Box 20)
  - 1927
    - Color in Architecture (Box 20)
  - 1939
    - A Search for Simplicity – Japan (Box 20)
  - 1941
    - "Commuting to Cumuto" (Box 20)
  - 1942
    - White Plains (Box 20)
  - 1943
    - Columbia Planning Seminar (Box 20)
    - London, Winter (Box 20)
  - 1944
    - England Trip, Articles and Talks (Box 20)
    - University of Toronto (Box 20)
  - 1946
    - The Architect and the Post-War World (Box 20)
    - Princeton University Bicentennial Conferences (Box 21)
  - 1947
    - The Contemporary Architect and His Education (Box 21)
    - Dialogue: Korax - Eubatos (Box 21)
    - In quest of Eutopia (Box 21)
  - 1948
    - "Humans + Materials=Architecture" (Box 21)
  - 1949
    - American Society of Landscape Artists (Box 21)
    - The Architect as a Modern (Box 21)
    - The Architect Asks Why (Box 21)
    - California Council of Architects Convention (Box 21)
    - Citizens' Housing and Planning Council (Box 21)
    - Cairo (Box 21)
    - The Design of Communities (Box 21)
    - The Field of the Architect (Box 21)
    - New York Building Congress (Box 21)
    - New York Chapter - American Institute of Architects (Box 21)
    - The Problems of Our Education (Box 21)
    - Public Relations (Box 21)
    - The Purpose of Light (Box 21)
    - Seminars and Their Possibilities (Box 21)
    - Symposium - Pennsylvania Society of Architects (Box 21)
    - Urban Planning and the Architect (Box 21)
  - 1950
    - Architecture:Profession or Business (Box 21)
    - Atlanta, Georgia (Box 21)
    - The Education Necessary to the Professional Practice of Architecture (Box 21)
    - Hospital Consultants (Box 21)
    - "Is This Peace?" (Box 21)
    - Laboratory Design (Box 21)
    - Rotch Scholars - In Memorium to Annie Lamb (Box 21)
    - Trip to Salt Lake City, Denver, West Coast (Box 21)
    - Texas and New Orleans (Box 21)
    - We Need Teachers (Box 21)
    - The World We Architects Might Help to Build (Box 21)
  - 1951
    - The Architect and the University Library (Box 21)
    - Behind the Venetian Blind (Box 21)
    - Building Trades Employers' Association (Box 21)
    - California - February (Box 21)
    - Friends of the Columbia Libraries (Box 21)
    - Good Design in Architecture (Box 21)
    - Hospitals - Yale University (Box 21)
    - L'Habitation De LeCorbusier (Box 21)
    - New Building Techniques and Clay Products (Box 21)
    - The Strange Flowers of Anonymity (Box 21)
    - The Thoughts of Others (Box 21)
  - 1952
    - Building for the Tropics (Box 21)
    - Designing Conveniences for Research (Box 21)
    - The Education of the Architect (Box 21)
    - The Education of the Architect in America (Box 21)
    - Harvard - Graduate School of Design (Box 21)
    - The Human Use of Architecture (Box 22)
    - Illuminating Engineering Society (Box 22)
    - Impact of the Automobile on the American City (Box 22)
    - Monsanto (Box 22)
    - The Rise of the Factory Style (Box 22)
    - Society of Architectural Historians (Box 22)
  - 1953
    - Articles on Laboratories (Box 22)
    - Industrialization of Buildings (Box 22)
    - Laboratory Design (Box 22)
    - Luxembourg Cemetery (Box 22)
    - St. Wilfrid Club (Box 22)
    - Urbanity of Form (Box 22)
  - 1954
    - Architecture at Mid-Century (Box 22)
    - Beauty in Wood (Box 22)
    - Expenses (Box 22)
    - The Fly in the Amber (Box 22)
    - The Human Use of Architecture (Box 22)
    - The Machine, Aesthetics, and Architecture (Box 22)
    - New York University - Administration of Research (Box 22)
    - Presidential Advisory Committee on Housing (Box 22)
    - Where Do You Go From Here? (Box 22)
  - 1955
    - Arts Forum - Columbia University (Box 22)
    - Chemical Week (Box 22)
    - Expenses - London, Dublin, Holland, Paris, Berlin (Box 22)
    - Frank Lloyd Wright Testimonial Dinner (Box 22)
    - Montclair Library (Box 22)
  - 1956
    - American Society of Civil Engineers (Box 22)
    - Architectural Engineering (Box 22)
    - Building Materials (Box 22)
    - City Planning and Architecture Today (Box 22)
    - Classics vs. Poppycocks and Hit Parades (Box 22)
    - Cooper Union (Box 22)
    - Masonry Walls in Modular Dimensions (Box 22)
    - Mies Van der Rohe (Box 22)
    - Outrage - Committee on Housing, Westchester County (Box 22)
    - The Space Devoted to God and How Man Can Give lt Light (Box 22)
  - 1957
    - The Aesthetics of the Modern City (Box 22)
    - American Institute of Decorators Conference, Dallas (Box 22)
    - The Architecture of Our National Capital (Box 22)
    - Architecture and Today's Living (Box 22)
    - "Architektura" - United States Information Agency (Box 22)
    - Benjamin Franklin Stiftung - Dedication Address (Box 22)
    - Centennial Banquet - American Institute of Architects (Box 23)
    - Quality, Princeton University (Box 23)
  - 1958
    - American Institute of Architects (Box 23)
    - American Institute of Architects - Convention (Box 23)
    - Book and Author Supper Club, Cosmos Club (Box 23)
    - The Federal City (Box 23)
  - 1959
    - Books - Design and Contents (Box 23)
    - Essence of Tradition (Box 23)
    - Geometry of Man-made Landscape (Box 23)
    - Paradise Here and Now (Box 23)
    - Paris (Box 23)
    - Speech - National Citizens' Planning Conference (Box 23)
    - Westchester Citizens' Planning Conference (Box 23)
  - 1960
    - Building Research Institute (Box 23)
  - 1961
    - The Basis of Design (Box 23)
  - 1962
    - The Impact of the Automobile on the American City (Box 23)
    - Landscaping (Box 23)
  - 1968
    - The City (Box 23)
    - Diversions (Box 23)
    - In Search of a Culture (Box 23)
  - 1969
    - Tax Reform and Government of Cities (Box 23)
- Berlin files
  - Additional Work (Box 23)
  - Bank Correspondence (Box 23)
  - Ben Franklin Foundation (Box 23)
  - Berlin Building (Box 23)
  - Berlin Hospital Survey Meetings (Box 23)
  - Berlin Hospital Survey Miscellaneous (Box 23)
  - Bids (Box 23)
  - Board Meetings, 3 folders (Box 23)
  - Business Report, 3 folders (Box 23)
  - Ceremonies, 3 folders (Box 23)
  - Construction Data (Box 23)
  - Contract (Box 23)
  - Convocation (Box 24)
  - Cornerstone (Box 24)
  - Correspondence (Box 24)
  - Directors and Officers Documents (Box 24)
  - Excavation and Foundation (Box 24)
  - Expenses, 6 folders (Box 24)
  - Finances, 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Gifts (Box 24)
  - Hospital Survey - Finance (Box 24)
  - Interbau (Box 24)
  - Management and Use of Hall (Box 24)
  - Mayor Suhr (Box 24)
  - Meetings (Box 24)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 24)
  - Negatives (Box 24)
  - News Clippings (Box 24)
  - Payments (Box 24)
  - Photographs (Box 24)
  - Photographs (Box 25)
  - Photographs for Publicity (Box 25)
  - Progress Reports, 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Richtfest Ceremonies (Box 25)
  - Speeches, 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Stubbins (Box 25)
  - Transfer Funds (Box 25)
  - United States Information Agency (Box 25)
  - Berlin Booklets - Studies, 9 volumes (Box 25)
- Massachusetts Institute of Technology Library files
  - Acknowledgements (Box 25)
  - Alumni Association (Box 25)
  - Book Plate (Box 25)
  - Booklets (Box 25)
  - Books - Acquired or Purchased (Box 26)
  - Club of New York (Box 26)
  - Committee Formation (Box 26)
  - Desiderata (Box 26)
  - Finance (Box 26)
  - Footnotes, 6 folders (Box 26)
  - General (Box 26)
  - Gifts (Box 26)
  - Membership (Box 26)
  - Miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 26)
  - Other Libraries (Box 26)
  - Other Schools (Box 26)
  - Program for Dedication (Box 26)
  - Publicity (Box 26)
  - Purchases (Box 26)
  - School of Architecture (Box 26)
  - Special Collections (Box 26)
  - Visiting Committee, 2 folders (Box 26)
  - Friends of the Library
    - 1935-1940 (Box 26)
    - 1936-1946, 24 folders (Box 27)
  - Index Card File (Box 27)
  - Notebooks, 4 volumes (Box 28)
- Trinidad files